diabetesforecast.org 2019-05-24

# Privacy Policy: American Diabetes Association®

_Updated May 25, 2018_

## Our Commitment to Privacy

Your privacy is important to us. To protect your privacy, we provide this notice explaining our information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used.

### Collection and Use of Personal Information

**What is Personal Data?**

Personal Data (also referred to in this policy as Personal Information) means any information relating to a natural person who can be identified by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification/account number, location data, an online identifier, or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural, or social identity of that person.  
**  
Personal Information We Collect**

When you visit the ADA Websites, there are five types of information you might provide to us: contact information you knowingly choose to disclose; registration information when registering for an event, billing information when you donate, join, subscribe, or make a purchase; demographic or other information about you; and technical information collected by us as you interact with our websites.

**Contact Information**

In some areas of the ADA Websites, we request that you provide personal information, such as your name, address, e-mail address, and telephone number.

**Donor and Purchaser Information**

In some areas of the ADA Websites, we request that you provide your credit card number, contact information, and other billing information. **

Registration Information

**

In some areas of the ADA Websites, we request that you provide personal information, such as your name, address, e-mail address, and telephone number.

**Demographic Information**

In some areas of the ADA Websites, we collect demographic information such as your age, career, preferences, gender, educational degrees, ethnic background, interests, and diabetes affiliation. Sometimes, we may collect a combination of information types. Examples of areas of the ADA Websites where we may collect personal or combined personal and demographic data are pages where you can donate to the ADA, sign up to be a member (professional or general), register for a program or event, or purchase a product.

**Technical Information**

We also may gather certain information about your use of our site, such as what areas you visit and what services you access. Moreover, there is information about your computer hardware and software that we may collect. This information can include, without limitation, your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times, and referring website addresses. Some of this information is collected through the use of cookies (described below).

### Use of Personal Information

The information collected may be used by ADA for the purpose of providing you with the content you request, operating and improving the ADA Websites, providing a positive user experience, and delivering the products and services that we offer. 

We may also use the information we gather to inform you of other products or services available from the ADA Websites or to contact you about your opinion of current products and services or potential new products and services that may be offered. 

We may use your contact information in order to send you e-mail, postal mail, or other communications regarding updates at the ADA, such as newsletters, diabetes information, event and programmatic information, and additional listings which may be of interest to you. We may also use it to send you information about third-party products and services that match your interests and preferences, if you opt in for this communication. The nature and frequency of these messages will vary depending upon the information we have about you. In addition, at the time of registration for certain services, you have the option to elect to receive additional communications, information, newsletters, and promotions relating to topics that may be of special interest to you. 

If in the future we intend to process your Personal Data for a purpose other than that for which it was collected, we will provide you with information on that purpose and any other relevant information including the option to opt out. 

Part of our mission is to improve the lives of all people affected by diabetes, and we do that by providing appropriate information. We do not provide your name and address or email to outside parties, except as described here. To learn more about our encryption policies, please review the section on "Protecting Personal Information" (below).

For EU-based visitors and subscribers, the following table provides information required by the GDPR relating to our use of your personal information.

**Personal Information**

| 

**Legal Basis for Processing**  
  
---|---  
Contact information, including name, address, e-mail address, and telephone number.

Purchaser information, including credit card number, contact information, and billing information.

Demographic information, including age, preferences, gender, educational degrees, ethnic background, interests, and diabetes specific information.

Technical information, including your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times, and referring website addresses.

| 

Consent to provide you with the content you request, as necessary for the performance of a contract.

Necessary to provide you with the content you request.

Legitimate purpose of providing tailored content to you.

Legitimate purpose of authenticating subscribers and optimizing website performance.  
  
### Retention of Personal Information

We retain indefinitely all the personal information we gather about visitors or subscribers as necessary to fulfill our contract with you. We retain indefinitely certain anonymized information we gather about visitors or subscribers for the legitimate purpose of performing website analytics and providing use of our website to all visitors in an efficient, practical, and relevant way. If there is no legal basis or other requirement for keeping your data AND after there has been no activity from you for seventy-two (72) months, your data that is no longer required will be purged.

### Sharing of Personal Data

We do not share or disclose your personal information to third parties except as set forth below:

**Personal Information      **

| 

**Purpose for Sharing**  
  
---|---  
  
Technical information

Technical information

Contact information

Contact information

Contact information

| 

With ADA business partners for the legitimate purpose of understanding usage patterns for ADA Websites and those of our partners.

With web hosting and other technical service providers for the legitimate purpose of hosting our web servers and ensuring information security for our networks.

With consultants and vendors for the legitimate purpose of providing customer support and marketing assistance.

With credit card processors for purposes of processing credit card transactions in connection with the donors and subscriber’s contract with the ADA websites.

With our business partners, with your consent, for the purposes of providing you with products or services tailored to your interests and preferences.  
  
In addition, we disclose personal information if legally required to do so, if requested to do so by a governmental entity, or if we believe in good faith that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to legal requirements or comply with legal process; (b) protect the rights or property of ADA; (c) prevent a crime or protect national security; or (d) protect the personal safety of users or the public.

In the event any one or all of the ADA Websites become the subject of a bankruptcy proceeding, whether voluntary or involuntary, the ADA or its trustee in bankruptcy may sell, license, or otherwise dispose of such information in a transaction approved by the bankruptcy court as is legally required.

In the event the ADA business is acquired in whole or part by a third party by way of merger, consolidation, or purchase, we will disclose and transfer such information to the third party.

The ADA may also share aggregated anonymous information about visitors to ADA Websites with its clients, partners, and other third parties so that they may understand the kinds of visitors to the ADA _ _ Websites and how those visitors use the site.

### Your Rights under the GDPR with regard to your Personal Data

Under the GDPR, EU-based visitors and subscribers have the rights to request from us access to Personal Data we store about you, to amend (or rectify) this data, to restrict our processing of the Personal Data, to erase the data, and to receive a copy of the data in a structured, commonly used, and machine-readable format (data portability). If you wish to invoke a right under the GDPR, you may contact us at [dataprotection@diabetes.org](mailto:dataprotection@diabetes.org). Please use the subject line “GDPR Request” in the subject line. Your e-mail should include a sufficiently detailed description of the GDPR right with which you seek assistance along with appropriate contact information. We may need to contact you for further information. ADA will notify you if your request has been granted or declined, or if exemptions apply. 

If you have provided consent for the processing and storing of your data, you have the right (in certain circumstances) to withdraw that consent at any time, which will not affect the lawfulness of the processing before your consent was withdrawn. 

You have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) if you believe that we have not complied with the requirements of the GDPR with regard to your Personal Data.

### Information You Post

If you post any personal information in public and/or social network areas of the ADA Websites, e.g., in online community forums or chat rooms, the information disclosed may be displayed to other users of these services and may be collected and used by others over whom we have no control. ADA is not responsible for the use made by third parties of information you post or otherwise make available in public areas of the ADA Websites and communities. If you remove information that you have made public on ADA Websites and communities, copies may remain viewable in cached and archived pages of the ADA Websites or if others have copied or saved that information.

### Opt-In and Opt-Out Choices

The registration forms and other sections of the ADA Websites where we collect your information provide you with relevant opt-in and opt-out choices regarding promotional activity and other communications with you. To access your information, determine your preferences and our opt-in/opt-out online preferences, you may go to our Constituent Center and login at <https://donations.diabetes.org/site/SPageServer?pagename=CC_Profile>.

### E-mail

**E-mail to Donors and Participants:** Donors to ADA and Participants of ADA events and programs may opt in for first- or third-party informational e-mails or opt out of all e-mail communication, except transactional emails, such as donation receipts and event/program specific information registered, you may go to our Constituent Center and login at <https://donations.diabetes.org/site/SPageServer?pagename=CC_Profile>.

**E-mail to Subscribers:** Paid subscribers to ADA publications may also opt in for first- or third-party informational e-mails or opt out of all e-mail communication (with the exception of subscription renewal information) by contacting ADA at [dfocustserv@cdsfulfillment.com](mailto:%20dfocustserv@cdsfulfillment.com).

**E-mail to Members:** ADA professional membership and journal members may opt in for first- or third-party informational e-mails or opt out of all e-mail communication, except transactional emails, such as subscription renewal, at [membership@diabetes.org](mailto:%20membership.@diabetes.org).

**E-mail to Users who have submitted a Request for Information:** Individuals who have requested specific information from the ADA such as, but not limited to, e-newsletters, living with Type 2 Diabetes, Living with Type 1 Diabetes, Diabetes Food Hub related information, Diabetes Risk Test, etc. are agreeing that ADA may contact them by e-mail in exchange for these free services. Users who fall under the CASL and GDPR regulations may opt in to or opt out of e-mails from ADA. Users can also opt in for third-party informational e-mails.

  * Where permitted by law, users who do not wish to receive e-mail related to these activities or newsletters may cancel such services by following the unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of any e-mail message from ADA or go to the Constituent Center and update preferences.
  * Users who do not wish to receive e-mail may follow the unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of any e-mail message from ADA or go to the Constituent Center and update preferences.

The above are examples of opt-in/opt-out options and are not intended to describe every option on the ADA websites.

### Links to Other Sites

The ADA Websites may provide links to other World Wide Web sites or resources. You acknowledge and agree that the American Diabetes Association has no control over such sites and resources and is not responsible for the availability of such external sites or resources, and does not endorse and is not responsible or liable for any Materials, advertising, products, or other materials on or available from such sites or resources or those sites’ data collection or privacy policies. You further acknowledge and agree that the American Diabetes Association shall not be responsible or liable, directly or indirectly, for any damage or loss caused or alleged to be caused by or in connection with use of or reliance on any such Materials or goods available on or through any such site or resource or those sites data collection or privacy policies.

### Monitoring of Information and Cookies

We monitor customer traffic patterns and site usage to help us develop the design and layout of the American Diabetes Association website. We may also use the information we collect to occasionally notify you about important changes to the websites, new services or features offered by the American Diabetes Association, and special offers and information we think you will find valuable. If you would rather not receive this information, please contact us through one of the channels identified in "How to Correct or Update Information" (below).

Google Analytics is used to analyze traffic to this website. Google Analytics does not maintain individual profiles for visitors, nor does Google Analytics collect data that might identify the individual visitor. Google Analytics only collects aggregate data. Click here for more information about the Google Analytics [privacy policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en).

We collect standard information, by way of a cookie, to help us evaluate how our sites are being used. A cookie is a small uniquely identifiable text file that is stored on your machine. A cookie collects information that is used for statistical purposes and does not identify you in any way.

Our sites use cookies to keep track of your shopping cart and to make sure you don't see the same content repeatedly. We use cookies to deliver information specific to your interests and to save your password so you don't have to re-enter it each time you visit our site.

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can change your browser settings to prevent that. Even without accepting cookies, you can still use most of the features throughout the American Diabetes Association Websites.

Often times, we may use certain advertising networks and exchanges that participate in the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI). NAI has developed a tool that allows consumers to opt out of certain interest-based advertising delivered by NAI members’ ad networks. To learn more about opting out of such targeted advertising or to use the NAI tool, [click here](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/). Please be aware that such opt-outs do not affect non-targeted ads. We are not responsible for the effectiveness of, or compliance with, any third-parties’ opt-out mechanisms or programs, or the accuracy of their statements regarding their programs.

### Protecting Personal Information

We are concerned with protecting your privacy and data. When you make a donation, register for an event or program, place orders, access your account information or request information, we use a secure server. This secure server software, SSL (Secure Sockets Layer), encrypts all information you input before it is sent to us. Furthermore, all customer transactional data we collect is protected against unauthorized access with the use of digital certificates. Digital certificates for the American Diabetes Association are issued by VeriSign, one of the most established signers of digital certificates.

We provide reasonable technical, administrative, and physical controls to secure the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of personal information. If you have any questions about security on the ADA Websites, you may contact us at [dataprotection@diabetes.org](mailto:dataprotection@diabetes.org).

### Payment Processing

All credit transactions occur in a secure area of our site to protect you from any loss, misuse, or alteration of information collected. When you make a donation, subscribe or place an order online at any of the ADA Websites, your credit card information is protected through the use of encryption of web content using Transport Layer Security.

### Association Policies Regarding Disclosure of Personal Information

ADA, like many other non-profit organizations, occasionally makes available only our contributor names and postal addresses to companies, predominantly other non-profit organizations. In addition, member and donor names are provided to a credit card vendor as part of our affinity program. Names of Tour de Cure® participants may be provided to local bike shops. These practices help us reduce costs of reaching more individuals with our diabetes-related information. These companies are carefully screened. 

Names/addresses are provided on a one-time basis; therefore, these companies will not have continued access to your name and address unless you respond to them directly, which you are free to do or not to do. 

You can request that we do not share, sell, or exchange your information for third party's fundraising or marketing purposes by emailing us at [privacy@diabetes.org](mailto:%20privacy@diabetes.org). (If you use more than one email address, postal address or telephone number, please identify each one.) The American Diabetes Association may provide aggregate statistics about our customers, sales, traffic patterns, and related site information to reputable third-party vendors, but these statistics will include no personal identifying information.

### Our Commitment to Children's Privacy

Protecting the privacy of the very young is especially important. We adhere to the 1998 Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA). For more information, visit the Federal Trade Commission's [COPPA site](https://www.ftc.gov/tips-advice/business-center/privacy-and-security/children%27s-privacy).

### Notification Guidelines

The Association does not send unsolicited commercial communications to individuals with whom they do not have consent/permission or a pre-existing or current business relationship. The Association provides all notified recipients with a clear, easy and effective method to unsubscribe to any and all online communications.

### How to Correct or Update Information

Here are the options for changing and modifying information previously provided. 

Email [privacy@diabetes.org](mailto:privacy@diabetes.org) or send a letter to:

American Diabetes Association  
2451 Crystal Drive, Suite 900  
Arlington, VA 22202  
ATTN: Customer Service Center

### Where to address your questions or complaints

If you have any concerns as to how your data is processed, you can contact:

American Diabetes Association  
2451 Crystal Drive, Suite 900  
Arlington, VA 22202  
ATTN: Customer Service Center

E-mail: [dataprotection@diabetes.org](mailto:dataprotection@diabetes.org)

### Changes to Privacy Statement

If we change our Privacy Statement for the ADA Websites, we will post those changes here so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information, and to whom we will disclose it. We welcome your comments concerning this Privacy Statement. Members who believe that we have not adhered to this statement may contact us by e-mailing us at [membership@diabetes.org](mailto:membership@diabetes.org). Non-members may contact us at [dataprotection@diabetes.org](mailto:dataprotection@diabetes.org). We will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and remedy the problem. Thank you for using the ADA Websites.

### Legal Requests

ADA reserves the right to share your information to respond to duly authorized information requests of governmental authorities or where required by law.

### California

Under California Civil Code Section 1798.83 (also known as S.B. 27), if you are a California resident and your business relationship with ADA is primarily for personal, family, or household purposes, you may request certain data regarding our disclosure, if any, of personal information to third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an e-mail to [dataprotection@diabetes.org](mailto:dataprotection@diabetes.org) with “Request for California Privacy Information” in the subject line. You may make such a request up to once per calendar year. If applicable, we will provide you, by e-mail, a list of the categories of personal information disclosed to third parties for their direct marketing purposes during the immediately preceding calendar year, along with the third parties’ names and addresses. Please note that not all personal information sharing is covered by S.B. 27’s requirements.

### Acceptance of These Terms

Your use of the ADA Websites shall indicate your understanding and acceptance of the terms of this Privacy Statement. If you do not agree with all the terms herein, you should not use the ADA Websites or services.

### Tell Us What You Think

The American Diabetes Association welcomes your questions and comments about this privacy statement, about the practices of the Association, and about your dealings with this website. Please send email to dataprotection@diabetes.org, or write to:

American Diabetes Association  
2451 Crystal Drive, Suite 900  
Arlington, VA 22202  
ATTN: Data Protection Officer

  * Last Reviewed: May 25, 2018
  * Last Edited: May 25, 2018
